# FRANCISCO PÉREZ HERNÁNDEZ

## BACKEND DEVELOPER

# \$

Mexico City



+52 961 372 34 12 devfcph@gmail.com



main--devfcph.netlify.app/

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish	Native Speaker
English	B1

### HARD SKILLS

C#, .NET	Java
PHP	Python
SQL Server	MySQL
Oracle DB	MongoDB
Git	VueJS
React	Angular
Swift	Visual Basic
AWS	GCP

### SOFT SKILLS

Self-Taught

Responsible

Collaborative

Analytical

Team Worker

Persistent

## CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum fundamentals certified
Cloud Engineering
Cloud Arquitecture
Google Cloud Essentials
Introduction to IoT
Aws Machine Learning
Foundations

## HOBBIES

Bicycle

Reading

Boxing

Chess

Concerts

*-* ...

Continouos Learning

# **PROFILE**

Software developer with a strong focus on backend development and extensive experience in SQL and noSQL databases. My dedication to software development, coupled with my analytical and problem-solving approach backed by logical and critical thinking, has been a key element in my contribution to multidisciplinary projects in the public and private sectors. My track record reflects not only adaptability to diverse environments, but also a constant commitment to excellence in software development.

# EXPERIENCE

## **AWS Cloud Arquitect, Grupo Salinas**

Oct 2023 - Present On Site

 Designed, built and tested cloud-native applications using modern development methodology and best practices, deploying to Amazon Web Services (AWS) leveraging AutoScaling, Infrastructure as Code (IaC) and serverless or FaaS technologies.

# **Java Microservices Developer, Grupo Salinas**

Oct 2022 - Oct 2023 Hybrid

- Developed and maintained microservices that were built with Java, increased performance by 10%, and reduced latency across microservices by 15% to improve user experience.
- Utilized Docker and GitLab to create and maintain container-based microservices, providing standardized and secure deployments.

## iOS Mobile Frontend, GoNet An Orion Innovation Company

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022 Remote

Designed user interfaces for iOS applications using Swift

Fullstack Developer, Gobierno del Estado de Chiapas

Oct 2020 - Oct 2022 Hybrid

- Developed web applications using Microsoft SQL Server, ASP.NET Web API and Vue.is
- Implemented agile software development methodology and used Scrum to maintain development progress.
- Developed intuitive and user-friendly interfaces that increased user engagement.

## **Fullstack Developer, Global Transfer MX**

Jun 2020 - Oct 2020 On Site

Developed web services with RESTful architecture, using Laravel PHP framework and Microsoft SQL Server for storage

# **Fullstack Developer, Induxsoft Data Services**

Aug 2018 - Jan 2020 On Site

- Developed client-server applications with the help of various technologies including JQuery, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C#.
- Implemented and tested a number of solutions resolving complex data issues while ensuring the robustness and scalability of the code.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Engineering in Technology and Software Development, Aug 2016
Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas – Jun 2022

Exchange Student, Universidad de Boyacá, Colombia

Jan 2020 -Jun 2020